# Abimbola Balogun

With 6 years of experience in React, React Native, and Javascript. Specialized in building and maintaining web and mobile applications for thousands of users, focusing on application security, responsiveness, and scalability. A team player with strong communication skills, committed to problem-solving and creating effective solutions that align with business needs.

# **Relevant Experience**

Frontend Software Engineer at Apex Systems

April 2023 — June 2024 | Greater Toronto Area ON | Canada

- Identifying gaps around the org-wide frontend infrastructure, drafting proposals and implementing optimized and scalable solutions.
- Utilized efficient coding and regular testing to ensure 95% of interactions responded within 2 seconds, handling peak loads and achieving 99.5% uptime. Critical updates were deployed within 24 hours, and minor updates within 72 hours.
- Resolved 90% of user-reported issues within 24 hours by troubleshooting and collaborating with customer support teams; ensured high user satisfaction and minimized downtime.
- Collaborated with UI/UX designers to translate wireframes and mockups into interactive and visually appealing mobile app screens, focusing on user engagement and accessibility.
- Conducting and mentoring several strategic experiments, refining experiences based on resulting metrics and learnings.
- Implemented fast and reliable data transformation and diffing mechanisms on the frontend for our data pipelines.
- Participating and incorporating learnings from real merchant interviews and research sessions

# Full-stack Engineer at OnePort365

Feb 2021 — March 2023 | Lagos | Nigeria

- Co-Led a cross-functional team to develop West Africa's first digital freight forwarding management application, serving 10,000+ clients.
- Championed the setup and configuration of a React based application, accurately translating complex designs into functional interfaces, architecting optimized database schemas, and crafting robust API endpoints.
- Developed a comprehensive booking system for freight forwarding using Typescript for the front end development, allowing customers to select shipment types (Import/ Export) and desired services including Ocean Freight, Haulage, Air Freight, Custom Brokerage and Warehousing
- Built, styled, and shipped high quality websites, design systems, mobile apps, and crossplatform digital experiences for a diverse array of clients using technologies such as JavaScript, TypeScript, React, CSS, Java, Contentful, and more.
- Implemented an integrated invoicing feature and seamlessly integrated with QuickBooks, enhancing financial management capabilities and streamlining finance operations for the team
- Provided leadership within engineering department through close collaboration, building tools to improve developer experience, and mentorship.
- Managed the deployment and maintenance of MongoDB clusters, ensuring high availability of the OnePort 365 web application which resulted in a 30% reduction in downtime.

Junior Frontend Engineer at Lenilabs

Jan 2020 — Feb 2021 | Lagos | Nigeria

Frontend Intern Dec 2019 — Jan 2020 | Lagos | Nigeria

- Implemented a highly developed GraphQL APIs for a high-traffic e-commerce web applications (https://www.artgidi.com/), improving data retrieval efficiency by 30% as well as building GraphQL queries and mutations to streamline data access, resulting in a 25% reduction in backend response times.
- Deployed and developed scalable GraphQL schemas for a SaaS application (https://www.mayfairdesignstudio.ng/), enhancing client-side data fetching and reducing payload sizes by 20%
- Created intuitive admin dashboards for e-commerce and e-Library applications, improving user management and data analysis, resulting in a 30% boost in productivity and data-driven decision-making.
- Crafted professional and responsive websites for corporate firms, showcasing their brand identity and driving online presence, resulting in a 40% increase in website traffic and user engagement.
- Engineered a web application for dispatch operations, integrating Google Maps for precise geolocation services, optimizing delivery efficiency by 25% and reducing transportation costs by 15%.
- Solicited and incorporated feedback from colleagues to streamline the software development life cycle, resulting in a 20% reduction in development time and improved team efficiency.

+1 (613)-978-4243 427 Cope Drive, Ottawa Ontario github.com/olorunyomi97 Abimbola's LinkedIn

## **Skills**

# **Programming Languages**

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, Sass, Python, Java, PHP, GraphQL

#### **Libraries & Frameworks**

React, Redux, React Native, VueJs, Vuex, Next.Js, Gatsby, Node.Js, ExpressJs, AngularJS, Tailwind CSS, Styled Components, Laravel, Code Igniter Jest, Bootstrap

### **Tools & Platforms**

Git, GitHub, BitBucket, Netlify, Vercel, Heroku, Digital Ocean, AWS, Firebase, Storybook, Webpack, Figma, MongoDB, phpMyAdmin, HTTP, RestfulAPIs, Context API, ReactQuery, JQuery, Babel, Storybook, Ajax, Postgres

#### Miscellaneous

Agile and Scrum Fundamentals, Market Research, SSL/OAuth, MacOS, Caching, DOM, UI/UX Design, Restful, NPM, Linux

## **Selected Projects**

## OnePort365

A comprehensive booking system for global freight forwarding, primarily using TypeScript, React, Tailwind CSS, and Node.js.

## **Mayfair Studio Designs**

To think forward, do more collaborative designs for a better future.

#### Abimbola's Website

Personal website built with Gatsby and deployed on netlify.

## **Education**

## University Of Lagos.

Bachelor Of Science in Computer Science. Lagos | Nigeria | 2013 - 2018

# **Lighthouse Labs**

Diploma in Web Development.

# **Interests**

Web Accessibility, Anime, Gaming